AHMED F. ALSOKKARY

CORPORATE PERFORMANCE IMPROVEMENT MANAGER

(Co-Creator of Smart Value EPM system)

https://drive.google.com/open?id=0B4WBvsR4vkuxMEFIQVZoazlEeTA

Cell: +966537176486
E-Mail: Ahm_Feh@hotmail.com
Nationality:Egyptian
DOB: 05/11/1976

PROFESSIONAL PROFILE

Performance Improvement & Development professional with 17 years solid experience including the implementation of the methodologies and technologies of Enterprise Performance Life Cycle in different business areas (Telecom, Contracting, Information Technology, Healthcare, Insurance, Manufacturing, etc.) by developing and planning the Business strategy, establish Performance Measurement framework, Collect Performance data to Assess, analyze, review, and deliver decision making Knowledge, dashboards and scorecards to complies with all business directives, Implement decision making support solutions on top of business intelligence platform supporting both relational and multidimensional data models of a unified enterprise data warehouse, Integrate and extract data from multiple data sources, deliver online analytical processing (OLAP) cubes, Integrate Business, Applications, Data and technology architectures to assure greater business value and deliver the highest quality and technology based services.

EDUCATION

B.Sc in Computer Science Faculty of Science - Ain Shams University 1999 Cairo -Egypt.

PROFESSIONAL CERTIFICATIONS

- Balanced Scorecard Master Classes and Workshops 2009 Institute of international research (IIR).
- SAP BUSINESS OBJECTS Universe design 2010 SAP Middle East & North Africa
- Continual Improvement & Quality Training Program 2010 Riyadh Military Hospital (RMH)
- Project Management Professional (PMP) 2007 HRD KSA
- Oracle 9i designer 2006 Oracle University.
- 7 Habits of highly effective people 2005 Franklin Covey
- All fusion Harvest change manager administration 2003 Computer Associates (CA)
- Oracle Certified Professional (OCP) 2000 Oracle KSA

DOMAINS OF EXPERTISE AND KNOWLEDGE

- Enterprise Performance Management / Balanced Scorecard (BSC) implementation
- Business Process Improvement / Lean Six Sigma and Statistical Analysis
- Customer Relationship Management / Customer Value Management.
- Marketing & Competitive intelligence.
- Business planning & corporate strategic planning.
- Business Analytics, Data Mining, Predictive Modeling and Scenario.
- Business Intelligence, Data Warehousing and OLAP Analysis
- Project, Program and Portfolio Management / PMI methodology.
- Research and Evidence Based Business Case for Strategic Business Change.

TOOLS & TECHNOLOGIES

- SAP BusinessObjects/Universe designer/ Crystal Reports /Webi/Xcelsius/Voyager/dashboard builder
- SAP Netweaver BW /InfoCubes/Infopackages/Data transfer process/Process chain/Bex analyzer
- SAP Business planning and consolidation /Oracle Hyperion planning & Budgeting.
- ORACLE BI Enterprise Edition (OBIEE) / Oracle Discoverer /Designer /Developer /DBA.
- INFORMATICA PowerCenter/ Administration Console/Workflow manager/Repository Manager/ETL
- IBM FILENET /process engine /process analyzer/process designer/process manager/IBM Rational
- Microsoft SQL Server /analysis services (SSAS) / Reporting services (SSRS) / Integration services(SSIS)
- BMC remedy ITSM / process designer/Atrium CMDB/ Atrium service level management
- CA Service Desk/ CA ALLFUSION ERWIN data modeler/ CA All fusion Harvest change manager
- BSC (Balanced Scorecard) /Six Sigma/Total Performance Scorecard/ITIL / COBIT / TOGAF/CBAP
- QPR Balanced Scorecard / process guide /collaboration portal/administration

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

SEP 2014- PRESENT
ALGIHAZ Holding - Riyadh - KSA.
Performance Improvement & Development Manager

- Implement ALGIHAZ Balanced Scorecard programs, strategy maps, initiative matrix and linkage models covering all organizational key performance indicators, planning and developing the organizational budgeting, staffing, spending ratios, policies, procedures and controls.
- Optimize the business plans for corporate level and business units of (Energy, Distribution, Industrial
 projects and renewable energy), Implement the corporate, BUs and departmental Balanced scorecards
 covering the business strategy, SWOT analysis, SMART KPIs, strategic objectives, risk assessment,
 competitive analysis, operational plan and financial plan.
- Design and create effective bonus system across all Business Units (Energy, Distribution & Renewable energy) and Departments with a clear definition of validity, limits and payments mechanism. Cover a wider range of factors, reflecting a broader set of business objectives, take into account factors such as customer service, quality, safety, team and individual performance, profits and productivity.

- Design and develop the customer satisfaction survey, clarifies the selected strategies for conducting the survey, the type of data required and the techniques for collecting data, survey methodology, information analysis, recommendations and suggestion required for continuous improvement.
- Lead the implementation of Enterprise Resource Planning solution (ORACLE EBS finance, HRMS, projects management and supply chain) handle the developing of current process models, future process models, Gather Business Requirements, conduct reporting fit analysis, define data acquisitions and conversion requirements, conference room pilot workshops, user acceptance and go live.
- Lead process improvement projects that are cross-functional and inter-departmental using Six Sigma methodology and lean approach Business Excellence Model, Implement process Control and Management-process mapping, documentation, metrics, monitoring systems and process ownership.
- Identify and manage strategic revenue growth projects. Utilize statistical methodology for analysis and reporting to support corporate endorsement and implementation. Resulted in revenue growth, reduced waste, cycle time, and improved productivity.
- Develop a collaboration platform using SharePoint functionalities, task management, document control, knowledge sharing, Organization Browser, problem solving and decision making models, etc

AUG 2012 – SEP 2014 MOBILY - Riyadh – KSA. Business Analytics & Enterprise Performance Manager

- Implement activity based cost analysis for core and non-core functionalities across the operating models of
 revenue generating units (Business, Consumer, Whole sales & FTTH) by Identify and capture all of the
 resources and their associated costs, Identify and describe the various activities performed by the resources
 and allocate resource pool costs to activities.
- Handel the Integration of Business Intelligence & Performance Management with all systems and data sources required for Monetization analytical scenario from the following perspectives (Service Management, Project Management, Enterprise resource planning, Engagement surveys, Customer Relationship Management, Sales force, etc..)
- Implement Workforce optimization analytical and performance framework from Size perspective to assure the right number of people in the right roles, Skills perspective to assess what competencies and skills will be needed to meet future goals and shape perspective to assure right level of resources efficiently.
- Identify Enterprise Architecture Roadmap components based upon gaps between the Baseline and Target Business architectures, Ensure that the Implementation and Migration Plan is coordinated with the enterprise's approach to managing and implementing change in the enterprise's overall change portfolio.
- Determine & Establish the Organizational Architecture Capability, Develop a high-level vision of the capabilities and business value to be delivered as a result of the proposed enterprise architecture based on ADM approach.

- Assess the existing Performance Management framework to ensure that selected KPIs give us more value than it costs, the corporate KPIs have clear link to strategy and KPI definitions (and goals) still apply when the business or volume grows.
- Arrange with Big data team and product house for gathering BI & Performance Management requirements
 across the organization; assure the data availability and accuracy. Upload the required un-structured and
 semi structured data in a multidimensional structure.

SEP 2010 – AUG 2012 CITPOINT - Cairo – Egypt Business Intelligence & Performance Excellence Manager

- Implement industry based Balanced Scorecard programs, strategy maps, initiative matrix and linkage models covering all organizational key performance indicators, planning and developing the organizational budgeting, staffing, spending ratios, policies, procedures and controls.
- Architect and develop the governmental performance portal for Egyptian ministry of communication and information, BI implementation roadmap, Enterprise data warehouse design, data marts, OLAP cubes, data mining models, failover and load balancing architecture, administration, configuration, integration, SSO, AD authentication, security matrix, etc.
- Select and define a set of key performance indicators to monitor the staff efficiency and productivity by interactive dashboards and online notification & alert system .
- Implement Manufacturing BI /EPM platform for SAP modules of (MM,FI-CO,QM,PP,SD) on top of SAP BW standard and custom InfoCubes and create the relevant dashboards for selected KPIs.
- Establish PMO and conduct projects health checks and audits of all project documents including the business requirements, scope statement, project plan, project risk assessment, change requests, communication, stakeholder analysis, etc.

FEB 2007 - AUG 2010

Riyadh Military Hospital - Riyadh - KSA.

Business Intelligence & Enterprise Performance Manager.

- Implement Self service environment for Healthcare performance management allows users to create their own Scorecards, Dashboards, Analytics and Reports for pharmacy, outpatient, inpatient, medical records, etc. Creating Healthcare OLAP cubes and data mining models.
- Building a clinical KPIs library based on JCI Accreditation standards for hospitals and deliver decision making knowledgeable objects, statistical and predictive analytics.
- Establish and create a sustainable IT service management platform according to ITIL framework.
 Define and develop The IT Service Catalogue , producing the service design packages (SDP) for each new IT service, major change, or IT service retirement .

- Improve the performance of IT service life cycle by following Continual Service Improvement (CSI) model, measuring and monitoring services through interactive dashboards and scorecards, developing key performance indicators (KPIs).
- Migrate the ERP & Clinical Universes from Business Objects Universe Version BO 5.1.3 to version BO XI R2, publish patient activities operational dashboards and develop hospital wide Enterprise reporting Platform.
- Lead the project of defining and modeling the data dictionary and business glossary for clinical and administrative data marts. Integrate the Hospital data sources of HIS, RIS, LIS, ERP, etc... and Build MDM repository for master Patient Indexing.
- Building the ODS (Operational Data Store) as a Repository built to hold data extracted from the
 HIS as well as ERP to serve as a semi-synchronized Data Store. Develop and architect the
 Enterprise data warehouse, ETL processes, CDC and data quality techniques.
- Analyze, Benchmark, re-engineer and automate the current business process of administrative and clinical (Operating Theatre Management System, EMR, ICU, MMS, surgical Instrument Management, etc.). Develop robust document management capabilities.
- Implement Enterprise and data governance, risk and compliance effectiveness. Determine the leading common causes of performance variance using different analytical tools and techniques of Trend analysis, Cause-Effect analysis, root cause analysis, Impact analysis and Risk analysis, etc.

AUG 2002 - JAN 2007

National Company for Cooperative Insurance (TAWUNIYA) - Riyadh - KSA. Enterprise performance & Quality Assurance Consultant.

- Build centralized Management information Reporting, subscriptions and Notifications (event-driven & schedule-driven) platforms for Claims, Re-Insurance and Renewal processing. Architect and build Insurance SBUs (Motor, Medical, P&C) Data marts.
- Develop collaboration portal of Enterprise Business Intelligence objects, performance Management dashboards, data mining models and OLAP cubes for Insurance Marketing & Sales, planning and budgeting.
- Conduct Strategic analysis and planning workshops , Implement Corporate Balanced Scorecard and cascaded departmental BSC for Finance , IT , SBU's ,HR ,Marketing and Sales using best practice KPIs library. Analyzing and re-engineering Claims , Telesales and Renewal processes.
- Optimize System Development Life Cycle and Version Control for Electronic Bill Payments and all other Ebusiness applications integrated with Centralized national project. Following the IT governance frameworks according to ITIL and COBIT.
- Establish and create a sustainable IT service management platform according to ITIL framework. Define and develop The IT Service Catalogue for software, hardware and infrastructure components of (ERP, CRM, SCM, BI, EPM, Data Center, LAN, WAN, DBA, AD, Messaging, Firewalls, Platforms, Storage, Remote Access etc.).

AUG 1999 – JUL 2002 Saudi British Center (SBC) Riyadh – KSA System & Information Analyst.

- Analyze, Model the business process, Build the functional hierarchy diagram and control quality of the Institute Recording Management Systems for Saudi British Center.
- Customize statistical reporting modules for Saudi Standards , Metrology and Quality Organization to support The inspection of factories to get the mark of quality , export certificates and Accreditation.